Andreas Andreou

Senior Consultant

Andreas has been around in the professional software developing scene since 2014. He started as Java back-end developer but has since then been striving to broaden his skills in as many areas as he can (and finds interesting). He is willing to challenge himself and learn from the people he works with. He is currently interested in improving himself in front end development and CI/CD.

ThoughtWorks Experience

Senior Consultant, Reed Exhibitions, March 2017 - Current

Andreas worked with the client using C# to modify and update the API to better serve the needs of the user base. In one of the streams he collaborated with the rest of the team to produce a query language for the API using GraphQL (Javascript). The language was developed based on previous experience of the PO with the users and communication with them. Andreas also joined another where he helped develop a basic integration with the main client system to automate the creation of resources using NodeJS, AWS Lambdas and AWS SQS. Andreas collaborated with the tech lead to map out the requirements and managed the communication and coordination with the developing team of the main system. He also joined the client to an event where he helped showcase a prototype Android application and gather feedback.

Other Experience

Junior Developer, Leo Tech Consulting, March 2016 - February 2017

Andreas was assigned as a back-end and front-end developer for a bet exchange platform using *Groovy* and *Angular*. He refactored existing code for core functionality to a simple workflow using a modified Chain of Responsibility Pattern that made it easier to debug and understand. He also took part in the planning process with the clients and demoed the product at the end of sprints.

Junior Java Developer, Virtue Fusion, July 2014 - February 2016 Andreas was assigned as a Java junior developer.

Web Developer, Sleeping Sloth, November 2012 - June 2013

Andreas and his colleague created an online platform for athletic facilities to offer online reservation to their customers using *PHP*, *MySQL*, *HTML* and *Javascript*. He designed the database schema and created the back-end API. He also met with possible customers with his colleague to discuss functionalities and the design look.

Andreas Andreou Senior Consultant

Skills

Back-End: Java, Groovy, Javascript, C#, PHP, C

Front-End: HTML, Javascript, React, Redux, AngularJS, jQuery, CSS

Frameworks: NodeJS, Spring Boot, Hibernate, .NET Core, EF Core, Grails,

GORM, Nancy

Architecture: RESTful web services, AWS Lambdas

Cloud Services: AWS, Apigee

Database: MySQL, Oracle SQL, Microsoft SQL Server

Versioning: GIT, SVN

Education

He finished his Bachelor in Computer Science in sunny Cyprus and then moved to the UK to get his Master in the not as sunny but bike friendly Cambridge. In his free time he is studying to get some extra certifications like Oracle Java and similar. That's all folks.

Other Stuff

He knows how to speak English and Greek (and the Greek-Cypriot dialect). On his spare time he likes to relax walking around, going for a drink or a coffee with friends and colleagues and to read books and comics. 'Nuff said.